Max Weber
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1902-2007, Series 2:; (Box 1-5; 4.2 linear feet)
  - Joy Weber Correspondence, 1960-2007, 2.2:
    - Art Dealers Association of America, 1989, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Condolence Letters, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ellinger, Richard G., 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Ford, Alice, 1968-1985 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Kelly, Lionel, 1992-2001 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Moser, Joann, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - National Jewish Hospital, 1988-2005 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - North, Percy, 1969-2002 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
    - Requests for Authentification, 1994-2004 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Rubenstein, Daryl (Catalogue Raisonne Project), 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Seeman, Joan, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Story, Ala, circa 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Tarbell, Roberta, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Tate Modern, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Torosian, Michael, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Tucker, Richard, 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Weber, Maynard J., 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Werner, Alfred, 1960-1972 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - White, Maynard, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - General Correspondence, 1961-1974 (Box 4, Folder 50-57)
    - General Correspondence, 1975-2007 (Box 5, Folder 1-21)
    - General Correspondence - Undated, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Exhibition Files, 1919-2003, Series 3:; (Box 5-6; 0.7 linear feet)
  Exhibition files document various solo and group exhibitions of Max Weber's work. Most files were maintained by Joy Weber for exhibitions held after Max Weber's death. Files may include correspondence, planning documents, loan forms, lists of works, press clippings, exhibition catalogs, and photographs. Researchers should note that additional exhibition materials is filed in additional series, including Series 4: Gallery Files and Series 8: Photographs. There is also motion picture film in Series 9: Audiovisual Materials that includes footage of a Forum Gallery exhibition in 1975.
  Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Luxembourg Museum, "Exhibition of American Painting and Sculpture" (1919), 1919- 1920 (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
  - Fort Worth Art Center, Inaugural Exhibition (1954), 1954 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Jewish Museum, "Max Weber" (1956), 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - University of California Santa Barbara, "Max Weber Retrospective Exhibition" (1968), 1967- 1969 (Box 5, Folder 27-29)
  - Court Galleries, "Five Decades of Pioneering Modern Art by Max Weber" (1970), 1969- 1971 (Box 5, Folder 30-32)
  - Frame House Gallery, "Max Weber" (1970), 1970 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Pratt Institute, "Max Weber, 1881-1961: A 10th Year Commemorative" (1971), 1971- 1972 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - University of California Santa Barbara (1972), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Harbor Gallery, "The Collected Woodcuts of Max Weber" (1973), 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Forum Gallery, "Max Weber" (1979), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
  - Great Neck Library, "Max Weber" (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Jewish Museum, "Max Weber: American Modern" (1982), 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 41-43)
  - Forum Gallery, "Max Weber" (1982), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - High Museum of Art, "The Advent of Modernism: Post-Impressionism in North American Art, 1900-1918" (1986), 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Santa Fe East Galleries, "Max Weber: An Exhibition of Paintings" (1987), 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - High Museum of Art, "Max Weber: The Cubist Decade 1910-1920" (1991), 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
  - Jewish Museum, "Painting a Place in America" (1991), 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Museum of New Mexico, "Proto-Modern Photography" (1992), 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Museum, "Culture and Continuity: The Jewish Journey" (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Albuquerque Museum, "Georgia O'Keeffe: From 291 to New Mexico" (1997), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, "Max Weber" (1999), 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Albuquerque Museum, "Silent Things, Secret Things: Still Life from Rembrandt to the Millennium" (1999), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gerald Peters Gallery, "Max Weber" (2000), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Georgia O'Keeffe Museum, "Views of the City" (2000-2001), 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Gerald Peters Gallery, "Max Weber: Early Drawings" (2003), 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Gallery Files, 1926-2005, Series 4:; (Box 6-7; 1.0 linear feet)
  Gallery files include correspondence, price lists, inventories, artwork sales and loan records, exhibition planning documents, notes, gallery publications, and photographs. After Max Weber's death in 1961, files were maintained by his daughter Joy and include her notes and correspondence with galleries.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by gallery name. Documents are arranged in rough chronological order within each folder.
  - Associated American Artists, 1940-1943 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Associated American Artists, 1968-1975 (Box 6, Folder 11-14)
  - Bernard Danenberg Galleries, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 15-22)
  - Downtown Gallery, 1926-1936 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Downtown Gallery, 1950-1969 (Box 6, Folder 24-34)
  - Eva Lee Gallery, 1964-1973 (Box 6, Folder 35-37)
  - Forum Gallery, 1970-1999 (Box 6, Folder 38-41)
  - Forum Gallery, 1970-1999 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Gerald Peters Gallery, 2002-2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Harbor Gallery, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - J. B. Neumann's New Art Circle, 1934-1937 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Personal Business Records, 1906-2006, Series 5:; (Box 7; 0.7 linear feet)
  Personal business records include documents on sales and loans of Max Weber's artwork; scattered financial documents, such as cancelled checks, receipts, tax documents, and account books; and mortgage and property records. Also found are files regarding his participation in the American Artists' Congress, Artists Union, and art juries. Additional materials include records of gifts of Weber paintings to museums and universities, and numerous lists of works of art. Most files regarding artwork were maintained and added to by Max Weber's daughter Joy after his death.
  Files are arranged alphabetically. Items within folders are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Account Books, 1938, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Artists' Congress, circa 1935-41 (Box 7, Folder 8-13)
  - Artists' Cooperative Institution Agreement, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Artists Union, circa 1936-1940 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Artwork Framing, 1956-1957, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Artwork Labels, 1949-1968 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Artwork Restoration, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Artwork Sales Records, 1919, circa 1939-1984 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Artwork Sales Records - Krasner Gallery, 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1917-1941 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Copyright Registration, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Donation of Max Weber's Library, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Estate Tax, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Gift to Brandeis University, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Gift to Israel Museum, circa 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Gift to Jewish Museum, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Gifts to Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1985-1999 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Gift to Montclair Art Museum, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Gift to National Jewish Hospital, circa 1989 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gift to National Museum of American Art, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Gift to Newark Museum, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Gift to Santa Fe Concert Association, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Gifts to University of Minnesota, 1997, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Gift to University of New Mexico, 1995, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Gift to Yale University Art Gallery, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Insurance Certificates, 1932-1959 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Jury Panels, 1937-1959 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Lists of Works of Art, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Loan Agreements, 1935-1955, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Loan of Matisse Tile, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Loan of Picasso Painting, 1999-2006 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Loan of Rousseau Painting, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Loans to Museum of New Mexico, 1993-2002 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art Electronic Reproductions, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Mailing Receipts, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Pepsi-Cola Art Competitions, 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Property Records, 1921-1952 (Box 7, Folder 48-50)
  - Receipts, 1906-1960 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Tax Documents, 1938, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art Audio Guide, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Workshop at Bowling Green State University, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Writings, circa 1910s-1999, Series 6:; (Box 7-8; 0.6 linear feet)
  Writings consist of draft manuscripts and typescripts by Max Weber as well as writings by others. Weber's writings concern art theory, impressions of other artists such as Matisse, Rousseau, and Cezanne, as well as social and political issues. Miscellaneous writings by Weber include untitled essays, fragments, notes, draft lectures and speeches, and lists. Writings by others include essays about Weber as well as writings by his friend Temple Scott and poetry by his wife Frances.
  Writings by Weber are filed first followed by writings by others which are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - "Adult Dolls", circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - "Art Consciousness", 1916 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - "Art Eternal", undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - "At the Tomb of Mrs. L. R. Miller", circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - "The Matisse Class", 1951 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - "Statement to National Gallery", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - "Whither American Art?", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Annotated Proofs of Essays, circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pocket Notebook, circa 1910s (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Writings on Cezanne, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Writings on Plastic Art, circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Writings on Rousseau and Matisse, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes, 1910s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 9-15)
  - Notes Taken by Students in Life-Class at Art Students League, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Katherine Coffey, "Max Weber", circa 1959 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Percy North, "Max Weber, Pablo Picasso, and the Introduction of Cubism to America", 1999 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - O. John Rogge, "An Appeal to Moderates", circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Temple Scott, "The Faubourg Saint Bronnex: A Study of a Post-Impressionist Artist", 1911- 1912 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Temple Scott, "The Lady and the Singing Bird", circa 1910s (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Frances Weber, Poetry, circa 1916 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Alfred Werner, Manuscript for "Max Weber", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Unknown Author, "Hyphenated American Modernists: Mark Rothko's Peers", circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Unknown Author, "Max Weber", circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Printed Material, 1909-2008, Series 7:; (Box 8-10, 12; 2.6 linear feet)
  Printed material is extensive and includes exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations for solo and group shows of Weber's work, press releases, and two published booklets written by Weber: "Art Consciousness" and "Things." Also found are news clippings, magazines, brochures, newsletters, and publications produced by art organizations, schools, and museums. Also of note are four volumes of Artlover published by J. B. Neumann.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically. Items within each folder are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - American Federation of Art Publications, 1950-1959 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Artlover: J. B. Neumann's Bilderhefte, circa 1935-1936 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1970-1988, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Book, Le Neo-Plasticisme by Piet Mondrian, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Booklet, "Art Consciousness" by Max Weber, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Booklet, "Reminiscences" by Christian Bucheit, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Booklet, "The Story of the Armory Show" by Walt Kuhn, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Booklet, "Things" by Max Weber, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Booklet, "Triumphs and Slavery of Modern Art" by Alice Garrett, circa 1932 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Brandeis University Publications, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Brochures and Catalogs for Newly Published Books, 1914-circa 2000 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "The Bulletin of the Museum of Modern Art", 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Congressional Publications, 1937-1956 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Essays on Art (Not by Max Weber), 1916-2000 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Event Announcements and Programs, circa 1920s-2005 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1930-2008 (Box 8, Folder 41-44)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Lists of Catalogs, circa 1959, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1909-2004 (Box 9, Folder 1-27)
  - Exhibition Catalogs - Undated, circa 1930s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Entry Forms and Membership Forms, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Forum Magazine Excerpts, "The Artists Point of View", 1936-1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - International Institute of Arts and Letters Publications, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Museum Calendars, 1983-2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Museum Publications, circa 1930s-2001 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Magazines, 1929, 1940-1949 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, 1910s-2000s, (Oversize items housed in Box 12) (Box 10, Folder 8-17)
  - News Clippings - Undated, circa 1920s-2000s (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, 1935-2006 (Box 10, Folder 19-21)
  - Pratt Institute Publications, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Press Releases, 1937-1981 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Printed Material regarding Activism, 1930s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Printed Material regarding Benjamin De Casseres, circa 1920s (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Printed Material regarding Richard Tucker, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Ralph M. Pearson's Design Workshop Courses by Mail", circa 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - School Publications, 1930s, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1930s-1971 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - News Clippings, 1910s-1950s, (Oversize items from Box 10, Folders 8-17) (Box 12)
- Photographs, 1930s-circa 2000, Series 8:; (Box 10-11; 1.1 linear feet)
  Photographs include portraits and snapshots of Max Weber, depicting him working in his studio, participating in art juries, at art openings, and with his family. Also found are photographs of Weber giving a lecture at the Skowhegan School, and photographs of him at home with his family taken by International News Photo. Photographs also depict installation views of exhibitions and numerous photographs of Weber's artwork. Slides depict Weber giving lectures and exhibition installations.
  Photographs are arranged by subject.
  - Max Weber, circa 1930s-1960 (Box 10, Folder 31-33)
  - Max Weber in His Studio, circa 1950s-1960 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Max Weber with Others, circa 1940s-1960 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Max Weber at Whitney Museum of Art Exhibition, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Max Weber at Art Juries, circa 1950-1952 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Max Weber at Skowhegan School, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Max Weber in Ft. Lauderdale, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Weber Family, circa 1940s-1950s, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - House in Great Neck, New York, circa 1943 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Photographs Taken by International News Photos, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition Opening, University of California, Santa Barbara, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Installations, Bernard Danenberg Galleries, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Exhibiiton Installations, Forum Gallery, circa 1987-1999 (Box 11, Folder 4-7)
  - Exhibition Installations, Gerald Peters Gallery, circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Installation, Joan Avnet Galleries, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Installations, Miscellaneous, circa 1931-1947 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 11-19)
  - Photographs of Artwork used in Abrams Book, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1940s, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Color Transparencies, circa 1982 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Negatives, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Slides, 1957-1981 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1954-2000, Series 9:; (Box 11; 3 folders)
  Found here is one sound recording of a National Gallery program, "This Week at the National Gallery" which disucsses Max Weber. Also found is one unidentified film reel (8 mm.) from 1954 and four film reels (Super 8 mm.) from an exhibition at the Forum Gallery in 1975.
  - "This Week at the National Gallery: Charlie Ritchie Discusses Max Weber", 2000 January 1, (1 sound cassette) (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Film, 1954, (1 film reel) (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Forum Gallery Exhibition, "Max Weber", 1975, (4 film reels) (Box 11, Folder 26)